Guide to the William Shockley Papers SC0222
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1990-117
  - U.S. Army Scientific Advisory Panel (ASAP)
    - Communications/Electronics Subpanel, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Army SAP, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Army SAP, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - ASAP, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Annual fall meeting, Colorado Springs, 1958-10 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Operations Research Subpanel, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - O.R.D. 1957 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - ASAP, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - ASAP, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - ASAP, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Army Sci. Adv. Panel Annual Spring Meeting, Fort Eustis, VA, April 18-19 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Army SAP comunications-Electronics Subpanel, Wash., OC, Jan. 27-28 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Photographic brochure of Fort Bragg Airborne Corps (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Diamond Ordnance Fuze Lab (DOFL)
    - Diamond Ordnance Fuze Lab, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Diamond Ordnance Fuze Lab, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Diamond Ordnance Fuze Lab, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Diamond Ordnance Fuze Lab, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Naval Ordnance Test Station (NARS)
    - Naval Ordnance Test station (Nars) 1958 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Naval Ordnance Test station, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Naval Ordnance Test station, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Naval Ordnance Test station, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Naval Ordnance Test station, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - A.R.D.C. 1959 [empty] (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - A.R.D.C., 1958 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - ARPA (Advanced Research Projects Division), 1959 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - C.D.E.C., Fort Ord, CA, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - C.D.E.C., Fort Ord, CA, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - NASA Committee on Electrical Power Plant Systems (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - NASA, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - NASA-Meetings-Committee on Electrical Power Plant Systems (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Operations Research Society of America, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Operations Research Society of America, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - National Security Agency Scientific Advisory Board, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - A.G.A.R.D. (NATO) 1957 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Dept. of Defense, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Dept. of Defense, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Dept. of Defense; W.S.E.G., 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Institute for Defense Analysis, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Kalmus, Henry, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - ARPA, Washington, DC, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Advisory Group on Electron Tubes (AGET), 1957 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Human Engineering Laboratory [unfoldered] (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Missiles, Rockets, and Automation Fund, Inc. Technical AdvIsory Board, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Meetings (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - APS Thanksgiving Meeting, November 24-25 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - La Conference des Sommets, Brusselles, Belgium, Sept. 25-28 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Academy of Achievement, Monterey, CA, Sept. 8-10 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - AIME - Metallurgy of Semiconductor Materials, Los Angeles, August 30-Sept. 1 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Dept. of Defense-Limited War Group-June-August (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Electron Devices Conference, Stanford University, June 26-28 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Lecture, Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama, May 25 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Electronic Components Conf., San Francisco, May 2-4 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - APS Div. Solid State Physics-Annual Meeting, Monterey, CA March 20-22 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Caltech Industrial Association, Pasadena, Feb. 20-21 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - PGMIL Winter Convention on Military Electronics, Los Angeles, Feb. 1-3 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Cleveland Electronics Conference, Cleveland, OH, Jan. 31, 1960-Feb. I, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous Meetings (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Files containing correspondence, travel itineraries, invitations to speak, and other items pertaining to meetings and conferences, 1956-1960 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, travel requests, and itineraries related to conferences and meetings, 1956 Expense reports: 1957-1960 Personnel files arranged by year (1960), individual name, field, or organization (Box 18)
  - Personnel files (Box 19)
  - Europe 1950; correspondence 1952; expo vouchers 1951; Sigma Xi correspondence 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1990-126
  - Freshman Seminar, 1969; 11 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Freshman Seminar curriculum materials, 1966-69 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum materials, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Student Papers, 1969-70 (Box 2)
  - Text Books (Box 2)
  - Mystery materials-student experiments (Box 3)
  - Assorted reports and papers; paper models (Box 3)
  - Student papers and memos: Freshman seminar (3 notebooks) (Box 4)
  - Freshman Seminar Course materials (Box 4)
  - Audiovisual material
    - Audio recordings
      - Telephone calls, 1978-1985
        - 1978-06 - 1978-09, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1978-09 - 1978-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1978-10 - 1979-01, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1979-01 - 1979-03, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1979-03 - 1979-08, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1979-08 - 1979-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1979-10 - 1979-11, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1979-11 - 1980-01, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1980-01 - 1980-02, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1980-02 - 1980-03, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1980-03, 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-03, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
        - 1980-04, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-03 - 1980-04, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-04 - 1980-05, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-05 - 1980-06, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-06 - 1980-07, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-07- 1980-08, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-08 - 1980-09, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-09 - 1980-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-10 - 1980-11, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1980-12 - 1981-02, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1981-02 - 1981-03, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1981-03 - 1981-04, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1981-04 - 1981-05, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1981-05 - 1981-06, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
        - 1981-06, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1981-06 - 1981-08, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1981-10 - 1981-12, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1981-12 - 1982-02, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1982-02 - 1982-05, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1982-05 - 1982-06, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1982-06 - 1982-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1982-10 - 1983-04, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
        - 1983-04 - 1983-08, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1983-08 - 1893-09, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1983-09 - 1983-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1983-11 - 1984-04, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1984-03 - 1984-08, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1984-08 - 1984-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1984-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1984-10 - 1985-02, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1985-02 - 1985-05, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1985-05 - 1985-09, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1985-09 - 1985-10, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - 1985-10 - 1985-12, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
        - Cassette Tapes (phone recordings), 1985-12 - 1987-10 (Box 12)
        - Phone tapes, 1986-1988; 15 audiocassette(s) (Box 13)
      - Classes; TV Shows; Interviews; Talks; Lectures; Conferences; Radio shows, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
      - Debates, 1971-73; Talks; Radio shows; Freshman Seminar (FS 96b) 1971; Lectures; FS 92 tests, 1968, 1968-1973 (Box 7)
      - Discussions; phone conversations; restaurant conversations; KZSU; etc., 1970s; 21 audiocassette(s) (Box 13)
      - 1. Resolution re: Jensen-Battig, 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 2. After Acad. Recept., 1969-04; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 3. Three unlabeled reels, 3 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 4. WABC Stan Siegel-James Farmer (2 tapes), 1976-06-07; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 5. Shockley at YMCA in NY, 1971; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 6. Sigman Xi-Monterey, 1969; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 7. BTL Retirement Party, 1975; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 8. Cleveland Caucus-Dr. Shockley and Sid Andorn, 1975-04-25; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 9. Charlie McCarty, 1973-03; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 10. Hurst-Shockley debate and UW, 1973-11; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 11. Innis-Shockley, 1974-09-16; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 12. Debate: Shockley vs. Hurst, 1973-11; 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
      - 13. Shockley/McCarty, 1 audiotape reel(s); 1 audiotape(s) (Reel-to-Reel) (Box 7)
    - Video recordings: TV Show: People are Talking, 1984; Clark R. Mollenhoff (talk) 1983; TV show, 1972, 1972-1984 (Box 7)
  - Diaries, 1958-1959; 1962-1977 (Box 9)
  - Diaries, 1978-1985 (Box 10)
  - Diaries (sparse entries), 1966-1974 (Box 11)
  - Bell Labs: reports, publications, drawings (Box 11)
  - Microfilm
    - Roll# 14; #copies: 1 (pos.); Description: Business records -chron in and chron out:, June-July 1970 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 15; #copies: 1, Aug. - Nov. 1970 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 16; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Dec. 1970-March 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 17; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out: April 1971-May 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 18; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out: June 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 19; #copies: 2; Description: Business records - chron in/chron out: 1961-1965 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 20; #copies: 2; Description: Business records - chron in/chron out: July 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 21; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Aug.-Sept. 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 22; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Oct.-Nov. 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 23; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Dec. 1971 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 24; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Jan.-Feb. 1972 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 25; #copies: 2; Description: Business Records: March -May 1972 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 26; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, June-Aug. 1972 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 27; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Nov.-Dec. 1972 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 29; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Jan. 1, 1973-Feb. 28, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 30; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out: March-April 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 31; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out: May -June 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 32; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out: July 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 33; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Sept.-Oct. 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 34; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Nov. 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 35; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, 74-0.01-1.25 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 36; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, 75-0.01-61-3.10 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 37; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, 76.0.01-63-3-22 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 38; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, 78-0.01-80-16-02 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 39; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out: 80-17-01-63-13-17 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 40; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, 1974 July 67.1-1974 82-31-07 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 41; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Sept. 1974 1.0-Oct. 1974 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 42; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Nov. 1974-Nov. 1974 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 43; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Dec. 1974-86-00.01-Dec. 1974 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 44; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, June 1975-Feb. 1975 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 45; #copies: 2; Description: Chron in/Chron out: March 1975-March 1975 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 46; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out: April 1975-June 1975 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 47; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, July 1975-Sept. 1975 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 48; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Oct. 1975-Dec. 1975 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 49; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Jan. 1976-March 1976 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 50; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out: April 1976-May 1976 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 51; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, June 1976-Oct. 1976 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 52; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Nov. 1976-Dec. 1976 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 53; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Jan. 1977-July 1977 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 54; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Aug. 1977-Dec. 1977 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 55; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Jan. 1978-July 1978 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 56; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Aug. 1978-Dec. 1978 (Box 12)
    - Roll# 57; #copies: 1; Description: Chron in/Chron out:, Jan. 1979 00.01-Dec. 1979 31.04 (Box 12)
- Additional material, ARCH-1995-153
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1980 Jan-Aug (Box 1)
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1980 Sep-Apr (Box 2)
  - Chronological outgoing correspondence, 1980 Jan-1981 May (Box 2)
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1981 May-1982 Jun (Box 3)
  - Chronological outgoing correspondence, 1981 Jun-Dec (Box 3)
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1982 Jul-1983 Jul (Box 4)
  - Chronological outgoing correspondence, 1982 Jan-Dec (Box 4)
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1983 Aug-1984 Dec (Box 5)
  - Chronological outgoing correspondence, 1983 Jan-Dec (Box 5)
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1985 Jan-1986 Aug (Box 6)
  - Chronological outgoing correspondence, 1984 Jan-1986 Dec (Box 6)
  - Chronological incoming correspondence, 1986 Sep-1988 Oct (Box 7)
  - Chronological outgoing correspondence, 1987 Jan-1988 Oct (Box 7)
  - Material related to comments on "Profile of American Youth", 1982 Mar (Box 8)
  - Pentagon report by William Shockley (Box 8)
  - Binder related to materials in box 8 (Box 9)
  - Bell labs (Box 10)
  - Human Quality (Box 10)
  - Student papers and miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Diaries (Box 11)
  - Selected correspondence organized by correspondent (Box 12)
  - FREED #1 (Box 13)
  - FREED #2 (Box 14)
  - FREED material (Box 15)
  - Clippings from Stanford publications (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous research files and FREED material (Box 16)
  - Computer printouts with tape backup (Box 17)
  - Statistical research on home computer (Box 17)
  - Computer tapes (Box 18)
  - Lee de Forest autobiography (Box 18)
  - Bell Labs-personnel matters, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Research and Development Board (Washington, DC), 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Memos, etc., reproposed research on heredity 1968 [Stanford] (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Military reports, 1945-1946, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "Operational Research." A paper based on recent lectures by Sir Charles Goodeve, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Project 1968 [heredity]-memos, letters, taped conversation re 12 Nov. 1968 incident (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Project 1968 [heredity]-memos and correspondence (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Telephone conversation with Albert B. Lorincz, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Project 1968 [heredity], 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Draft of letter, 1969 Apr 24 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Bell Labs-correspondence re documents, 1947-1956 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Notes, report re weapons, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - PPI Scope Interpretation, 1944 Feb 12 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Photos-radar related (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Vectographs (2 photographs), 1944 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Travel expenses, 1942-1944 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Blackett, P.M.S. A Note on Certain Aspects of the Methodology of Operational Research, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Shockley, “Relative Technological Achievements in Weapon Characteristics in USSR and USA”, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - “Polly” story [use of loudspeakers in planes to broadcast message to enemy], 1950 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous U.K [war and military memos, letters, reports], 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Shockley, Och Langmuir, “On Extrapolating Computer Performance into the Future”, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Anti-Submarine File, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Bell Labs-Merit reviews of staff, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Problem students-verifying birth records, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Journals, 1942 May-1943 Feb (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Journals, 1943 Feb-May (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Journals, 1943 May-1944 Jan (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Journals, 1944 Jan-1945 Jan (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - A. R.’s notes: meetings, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1955-1959 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Research notebook #28, 1955-1959 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Research notebook #1, Beckman Instruments, 1955-1958 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Small notebook, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks (18 v.), [mostly stenographers notebooks, some used during trips], 1955-1962 (Box 20)
  - Daily Journals [3 v.), 1963-1965 (Box 20)
  - Daily journal, 1960 (Box 20)
  - Daily journal, 1961 (Box 20)
  - Audio tapes and microfilm (Box 21)
  - Personal letters from Marion, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Personal letters from May, 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Personal letters from Jean, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Personal letters from Alison, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Personal letters from Emmy (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Personal letters received [includes letters from above people staped together], 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Professional correspondence, incoming, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing letters, 1950-1954 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - “Genesis of the Transistor” by W. G. Gorton, revised by W.S., 1949 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Lecture on evolutionary sociology (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Audograph labeled “Nightmare about 6 Apr 1955” (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Shockley Semiconductor Lab (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Notes re "non-linear behavior of transistors" (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Jeannine Roger-letters (in French), photograph, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Notes [possibly re business troubles], 1957 May-Jun (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re job offers with Hughes and International Telemeter Corp., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Shockley, “On Research Department Productivity and Recruiting Practices”, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Christmas cards and notes, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Assessment of European labs and BTL, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Agreement with Beckman Instruments, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Discussions with Dr. Beckman, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Publicity-Knapic and Fairchild; letters re Knapic, 1957, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Founding contract of Fairchild Camera (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re Clevite Corp., Shockley Transistor Corp., and circuit clamp, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - “Human Relations” correspondence [re evaluation form for physics grad students and professionals], 1950 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Personal and family letters received, 1955 May-Jun (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Patent [electroopitcal control system], 1954 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Airline tickets, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence (personal and professional), 1955 Feb-May (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence (personal and professional), 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and financial records (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous scientific papers (one by Shockley) (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Packet on Kailani Village, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Memo re Fairchild investigation, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Financial records, Shawmut Bank of Boston, 1961-1963 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Ross Aiken, Video Color Corp., 1962 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Cache Valley Electronics, G. Smoot Horsley, 1960-1962 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Placer County property (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Financial records, 1959-1962 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Financial records [Fidelity Trend Fund securities] (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Clevite Corp., background to 1963 agreement (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Clevite Corp., correspondence, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Clevite Corp., agreement and correspondence, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Stanford University – appointment and other correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Automobile and boat papers; family information (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Hawaii property owned by Ross Aiken, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Bell Telephone Labs agreement; correspondence re “human quality problems” research, 1965, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - Basis for first report (1 of 5 – “Early Work”) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Basis for first report (2 of 5 – “Curves”) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Basis for first report (3 of 5 – “Computing and set-up for f and fq”) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Basis for first report (4 of 5 – reprint; “Computation jobs”) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Basis for first report (5 of 5 – notes) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Duplicate notes (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Report [Utilization of nuclear energy from fission of U235] (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Carbon - notes (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Papers re patent, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Project 18 [USA vs. USSR in technology], 1945-1946 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Report by Shockley and Fisk, Uranium as a Source of Power (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Report by Shockley and Fisk, Uranium as a Source of Power (1st copy) (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Uranium as a Source of Power (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Uranium as a Source of Power, Shockley’s copy (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - BTL notebook #17407, 1940 Jul-1941 Mar (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - BTL notebook #17006, 1939 Nov-1940 Aug (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Parts III and IV of report on uranium as a source of power (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Patent to E. Fermi et. al. for neutronic reactor, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Draft of possible arrangement between Shockley and Beckman, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Shockley, “On Research Department Productivity and Recruiting Practices", 1953 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - O.R. data; patent info [re “On Research Department Productivity and Recruiting Practices”] (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - O.R. data on salaries [re “On Research Department Productivity and Recruiting Practices”] (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Data on publications [re “On Research Department Productivity and Recruiting Practices”] (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Radar: reports, notes, memoranda, 1942-1945 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - BTL staff: info re offers accepted and declined, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - BTL staff: figures re offers accepted and declined, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Tablet of BTL graph paper (blank) (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Negative stats of four pages from BTL notebook #17006 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Loose papers from Shockley’s copy of “Uranium as a Source of Power” [re patent] (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Case 10-secret [radiant energy control system], 1952 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Uranium as a source of power-mss and ts copies of report (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Papers re exception to patent agreement, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - “A T.R. Project,” stencils, copies, original drawings, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - T. R. Project – correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Special Reports Administrative Memoranda (office copy), 1957 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Special Reports Administrative Memoranda (home file), 1957 (Box 24, Folder 7)